Jeannine Polivka



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a PhD Candidate in Econometrics at the University of St. Gallen. My key research areas include Macroeconometrics, Financial Econometrics and Time Series Analysis. In my job market paper, I offer new perspectives on volatility impulse response functions.

References:	► <u>Christian Brownlees</u>	▶ <u>Luca Fanelli</u>	► <u>Matthias Fengler</u>

EDUCATION	
PhD in Economics and Finance (PEF), University of St. Gallen, Switzerland Econometrics track (2019), Supervisors: M. Fengler, L. Fanelli Thesis project: <i>Structural volatility modeling</i>	02/2019 - 01/2023
M.Sc. in Mathematical Finance, University of Konstanz, Germany Thesis in Financial Econometrics: <i>Scaling laws in financial markets</i>	10/2014 - 10/2018
Financial Engineering and Chinese, Nanjing University, China (China Scholarship Program)	08/2015 - 08/2016
B.Sc. in Mathematical Finance, University of Konstanz, Germany	10/2011 - 09/2014
VISITING POSITIONS	
Visiting fellow at Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Host: C. Brownlees Visiting fellow at University of Bologna, Host: L. Fanelli	03/2022 - 02/2023 06/2022
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	
Research Assistant, Department of Mathematics and Statistics, Chair of Financial Econometrics, Professor M. Fengler University of St. Gallen, Switzerland	10/2018 - 02/2022
Quantitative Risk Methodology, Intern Credit Methodology Lombard Team UBS AG, Zurich, Switzerland	02/2017 - 07/2017
Financial Advisory, Intern Risk Management Analytics and Quant Team Ernst & Young Ltd, Zürich, Switzerland	09/2016 - 01/2017
Research Assistant at the Chair of Organizational Economics Department of Economics, University of Konstanz, Germany	01/2013 - 03/2015

TEACHING ACTIVITIES (DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS & STATISTICS, UNIVERSITY OF ST. GALLEN)

- Teaching fellow for Master course Time Series Econometrics
- Teaching fellow for Master course Econometric Methods for Financial Instruments
- Teaching fellow for Bachelor course Data Analytics in Finance
- Correction assistance and relief tutor for Bachelor level Mathematics A and B courses
- Tutor for Analysis (Department of Mathematics and Statistics, University of Konstanz)

JOB MARKET PAPER

Fengler, M. R. and Polivka, J. (2022). Structural volatility impulse response analysis, Economics Working Paper Series 2211, University of St. Gallen, URL: https://ideas.repec.org/p/usg/econwp/202211.html, submitted.

WORKING PAPERS

- Fengler, M. R. and <u>Polivka, J.</u> (2021). Identifying structural shocks to volatility through a proxy-MGARCH model, Economics Working Paper Series 2103, University of St. Gallen, URL: https://ideas.repec.org/p/usg/econwp/202103.html, revise and resubmit (Journal of Applied Econometrics)
- Dimitriadis, T., Halbleib, R., <u>Polivka, J.</u> and Streicher S. (2022). Efficient Realized Variance Estimation in Time-Changed Diffusion Processes, Technical Report, submitted.
- <u>Polivka, J.</u> (2022). Time-varying shock transmission in structural volatility models, Technical report, University of St. Gallen (HSG), ongoing.

CONFERENCE & SEMINAR CONTRIBUTIONS

- EEA-ESEM 2022, European meeting of the Econometric Society, Parallel Session: Macroeconometrics.
- QFFE 2022, International Conference on Quantitative Finance and Financial Econometrics, Parallel Session 1: ARCH. Parallel Session 2: High Frequency Data.
- BSE Summer Forum 2022, Barcelona School of Economics, Poster Session: Advances in Econometrics.
- CFE 2021, 15th International Conference on Computational and Financial Econometrics, Invited Session: Advances in Volatility Modeling.
- 2021 NBER-NSF Time Series Conference, Poster Session: Advances in Time Series Modeling.
- University of Bologna 2021, Department of Economics: Internal Seminar.
- SoFiE 2021. Annual Conference of the Society of Financial Econometrics 2021, Parallel Session: Volatility.
- SSES 2021. Annual Congress of the Swiss Society of Economics and Statistics, Parallel Session: Econometrics III.
- RMI 2021, NUS RMI 14th Annual Risk Management Conference.
 Parallel Session: Advances in Risk Management.
- CEQURA 2019, 10th Conference on Advances in Financial and Insurance Risk Management.

REVIEW ACTIVITIES

- International Journal of Forecasting
- Econometrics and Statistics

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Scholarship Doc.Mobility

Scholarship Deutsche Studienstiftung

Jane M. Klausman Women in Business Award

Scholarship China Scholarship Program

03/2022 - 02/2023

10/2011 - 10/2018

07/2017

Scholarship China Scholarship Program

08/2015 - 08/2016

ADVANCED TRAINING (DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS AND STATISTICS, ETH ZURICH)

- Multivariate Statistics, Bayesian Statistics
- Seminar: Machine Learning of Dynamic Processes with Applications to Forecasting

SERVICES

Student representative of the PhD in Economics and Finance (PEF)

10/2019 - 09/2021

LANGUAGES

German (native), English (fluent C1), French (fluent C1), Chinese (proficient B2), Italian (basic A2)